35. Hold on to your pocket money. One day you'll need to learn how to save money, even
if you don't have anything to save for right now. Get used to saving and budgeting now.
Then you'll have money when you do want something expensive and you'll be practicing for your
future. Tip 1. Be clear about how much money you have coming in. Do you get your allowance
weekly or monthly? Do you earn any other money? Total your money for the period you want to
budget for. Tip 2. Separate needs from wants. You need money for transportation. You want to have
money left over for snacks and games. Then decide which of your wants should get priority and which
ones you can let go. Tip 3. Make a budget. Once you know how much money you will have in a period
of time, you can decide how to spend it. Separate the money for your needs and don't touch it for
anything else. Then add up how much your wants will cost. See if you can make your needs and wants add
up to 90% or less of your total allowance. Tip 4. Put your savings, the 10% or more that you
aren't spending each month, far away. Put them in a bank or somewhere that you can't reach easily.
You'll be less tempted to use them that way. Tip 5. Write your expenses down, at least until you
can get used to what they are. This way, you'll know where your money is going and what you need
to do to hold on to it longer. Tip 6. Put a little bit away every day. Even if it's just change, get
used to having something left over. You'll be surprised at how much change adds up over months.